# **Enrique Rivera Jr**

2700 Nueces St, Austin, TX
(210) 717-0450 - erivera7240@gmail.com
github.com/Quantum-Impulse - https://enriquerivera.netlify.app/

Software developer with +4 years of experience building projects by myself and within groups which includes coding, testing, debugging, and optimization. Seeking to leverage my proven achievements into other areas within software to gain a better understanding of the professional field.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### FRC ROBOTICS

Lead Programmer (50hrs weekly), September 2017 - 2020

- Wrote computer code in C++, Java, and Python to make software for large scale robots to be controlled with a gamepad and to handle tasks autonomously using PIDs
- Used linux to program accurate computer vision systems to guide robots and shooting mechanisms to reach their targets
- Robots contained cameras, motors, pneumatics, accelerometers, ultrasonic sensors, limit switches, servos that all needed to be programmed

## **MLH (HACKATHONS)**

July 2018 - present

• Designed and developed programs with a team to achieve the theme of the hackathon. I have used C++, Java, Python, CMake, OpenCV, javascript, , html, css, scss, and node.js to build multiple projects

#### **EDUCATION**

# The University of Texas at Austin

Bachelor of Science in Computational Physics, August 2021 - Pending

Elements of Computing Certificate – Pending

### San Antonio College

Information Technology & Security Academy, August 2019 – January 2020

#### ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- **Technologies/Software:** CMake, OpenCV, Visual Studio, Jetbrains, Node.js, Express.js, Webpack, Three.js, Xampp, Babel
- Programming Languages: JAVA, SQL, HTML, C/C++, JAVASCRIPT, PYTHON, CSS/SCSS, KOTLIN
- Hardware: PCs, Linux, and Macintosh

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Google IT Support Professional Certificate – 2021